Every house has a history. This one has a legend.
Amityville: The Awakening is a horror film directed by Franck Khalfoun.
Belle, her little sister, and her comatose twin brother move into a new house with their single
mother in order to save money to help pay for her brother's expensive healthcare.
But when strange phenomena begin to occur including the miraculous recovery of her brother, Belle begins to suspect
her mother isn't telling her everything and soon learns they moved into the infamous Amityville house.
Belle Walker, played by Bella Thorne.
James Walker, played by Cameron Monaghan.
Joan Walker, played by Jennifer Jason Leigh.
Terrence, played by Thomas Mann.
Candice, played by Jennifer Morrison.
Dr. Milton, played by Kurtwood Smith.
Amityville: The Awakening is a 2017 American supernatural horror film written and directed by Franck Khalfoun and starring Bella Thorne,
Jennifer Jason Leigh, Cameron Monaghan, Mckenna Grace, Thomas Mann, Taylor Spreitler, Jennifer Morrison, and Kurtwood Smith.
It is the tenth installment of the Amityville film series and a metafilm taking place in the "real
world", where the 1979 original, its sequels, and the 2005 remake are all works of fiction.
Its plot follows teenager Belle Walker who moves into 112 Ocean Avenue with her family, who shortly find
themselves haunted by a demonic entity using her brain-dead twin brother James' body as a vessel.
Originally titled Amityville: The Lost Tapes, it was announced in May 2011, and was initially
conceived as a found footage-style film and a separate entry in the franchise.
However, the studio abandoned the film's original idea, and hired
Khalfoun to write and direct a new draft in early-2012.
Filmed in 2014, the film suffered numerous release delays before finally being
released for free on Google Play on October 12, 2017 and on DVD in 2018.
Amityville: The Awakening was theatrically released by Dimension
Films in a limited release on October 28, 2017.
The film had grossed $8.4 million worldwide and received mixed-to-negative reviews from critics,
with criticism for its generic writing, horror clichés and reliance on jump scares.
It is the last film to be released by distributor RADiUS-TWC, as the company shut down along with Dimension and their parent company,
The Weinstein Company, on July 16, 2018, following the sexual abuse allegations against its co-founder Harvey Weinstein.
The film explores themes of haunted house, sequel, supernatural horror.
The tone is dark.